Emerson, Harrington Files 5166
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Harrington Emerson Files
1846-1968
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Emerson, Harrington
5166
6.11 cubic feet
6.1 linear ft.
Records (documents), case files.
Correspondence, speeches, writings, studies, reports, and publications of Harrington Emerson.
3338540
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 26, 2003
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 01, 2016
Biographical / Historical
1853: Born Trenton, N. J. Son of Edwin & Mary Louies Emerson. Educated in
England, France, Germany, Italy, and Greece.
1870's: Married Florence Brooke, one son, Raffe
1876: Headed Modern Language Dept., Univ. of Nebraska
1882: Left university to engage in banking and real estate with his brother, S.D.I. Emerson
1885-91: Did special economic and engineering research work for the Burlington Railroad
1895: Married Mary Crawford Supple, 3 daughters, Louise, Isabel and Margaret
1895-99 Served as U.S. representative of a British syndicate Investing in America - investigated finances and operations of many industrial plants and mines, in Mexico, the U.S. and Canada
1899-01: Managed a glass manufacturing company
1901-07: Active as professional consulting management engineer
1904-07: Carried out the reorganization of the Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe RR; introduced a bonus plan, standard costs, accounting by tabulating machines, and planned maintenance for equipment and rolling stock
1907-11: Called one of the principal witnesses in the "Eastern rates case'
1911: Named to Civilian Expert Board on Industrial Management of U.S. Navy Yards to investigate the functions and conditions of the yards
1921: Appointed member of the Hoover Committee for the Elimination of Haste in Industry; assigned to cover the coal and railroad
Industries
1929: Attended the International Management Congress in Paris
1931: Died on Sept. 2, aged 78, in New York City
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, speeches, writings, studies, reports, and publications of Harrington Emerson. Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Speeches, writings, studies and reports are all arranged alphabetically by title. Publications are arranged alphabetically by author.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Management science.; Emerson, Harrington, 1953-1931.
3338540
- Correspondence, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Scope and Contents
  To Emerson Associates concerning finances; 49 p. to Alexander Wylie, Director, Interstate Commerce Commission re the Fundamentals of Railway Operating Cost Records; 39 p. addressed "To My Younger Associates & Clients" from H.E. discussing "Standards"; financial & business operations; New Year's message to associates mentions business outlook is excellent and many satisfied clients and routine.
- Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Contains letters from organizations describing benefits experienced from association with Emerson engineers.
- Correspondence, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  RE: a lecture by H. E. at Mass. Inst. of Tech.; expense accounts; to C. E. Knoeppel re proposing a periodical devoted to industrial competence; to Judge H. Gary re reduction of hrs. of work in steel industry and misc.
- Correspondence, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  From American Engineering Council RE: work of the Comm. on Elimination of Waste In Industry; substantial correspondence re transportation; Hoover Comm. on Industrial wastes; conditions in Mexico; conditions of the railroads; wastes in bituminous coal mining; correspondence RE: a report on bituminous coal mining; 19 p. The Railroad Situation; and other related.
- Correspondence, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Correspondence, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Continued correspondence between L. W. Wallace and Emerson re Comm. on the Elimination of Waste In Industry matters; copy of editorial "A Misfortune That is Disgraceful" and letter to editor of NY Times from Emerson re the editorial concerning deaths from yellow fever in Mexico; letter to R.G. Bruce, Vice-President of E.L. Bruce Co. explaining Emerson Company plans and changes; correspondence with unions & individuals re speech by Emerson on railroads before the NY Railroad Club; considerable correspondence concerning Emerson's work with the railroad companies; with Interstate Commerce Commission re revision of the ICC's Accounting System; with Lawrence Wallace, Federated American Engineering Societies, asking for Emerson to visualize what the engineering profession should do for modern civilization; with G. A. Green, Fifth Avenue Coach Co. re reduction of gasoline use on omnibuses; 4 p. confidential memo re mexican railroad; and other related.
- Correspondence, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Letter (1/4/18) New Year's Greeting to members of Emerson Co. suggesting everyone take an inventory of himself"; 9 p. to Paul B. Sweet, thoughts about the Emerson Co.; letter to members of the Old and of the new New York Agency (12 p. ) explaining differences in operation of the Agency; correspondence with H. W. Jacobs re assisting his company with explanation on what steps will be taken; with Encyclopedia Americana concerning an article; to employees re code of ethics; correspondence re railways of Japan; to members of the New York Agency concerning the merger into the Emerson Company; memos to employees re individual merit, salaries, etc.
- Correspondence, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Includes 20 p. paper entitled "Contract Workers" and their importance to Emerson Engineers; substantial correspondence to staff of EE concerning the organization and administration, bonus payments, staffing, contracts, meetings, financial situation and other related.
- Correspondence, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Correspondence, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Correspondence, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Correspondence, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  RE: liquidation proceedings of E. E., financial matters; report to staff (Feb.), 17 p. and misc. charts.
- Correspondence, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Routine, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Biographical Information (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Includes biographies; publication lists; notes about his career by Alonzo Falek & misc.
- Correspondence, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Correspondence, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Between Emerson Co. and Sidney Blumenthal Co. (NYC) concerning the investigation by Emerson Co. & recommendations for establishing efficiency methods; Christmas Greeting, 12/20/11 (9 p.) from H. Emerson (on Emerson Co. inter-office letterhead) discusses the efforts of the staff over the previous 3 years noting company pride, company "just on the threshold of the efficiency movement," the movement includes women's work as well as men's, & contributions regarding efficiency that the company has made as well as other subjects; 4 p. letter from Emerson entitled "Some Observations of Bermuda", 12/26/11.
- Biographical Information (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1846-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes copies of letters from Harrington's mother (Mary Louisa) to her brother (Will) spanning a 20 year period. Of note are the letters beginning with September 8, 1853
- Correspondence, 1846-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes copies of letters from Harrington's mother (Mary Louisa) to her brother (Will) spanning a 20 year period. Of note are the letters beginning with September 8, 1854
- Correspondence, 1846-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes copies of letters from Harrington's mother (Mary Louisa) to her brother (Will) spanning a 20 year period. Of note are the letters beginning with September 8, 1855
- Correspondence, 1846-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes copies of letters from Harrington's mother (Mary Louisa) to her brother (Will) spanning a 20 year period. Of note are the letters beginning with September 8, 1856
- Correspondence, 1846-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes copies of letters from Harrington's mother (Mary Louisa) to her brother (Will) spanning a 20 year period. Of note are the letters beginning with September 8, 1857
- Correspondence, 1846-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes copies of letters from Harrington's mother (Mary Louisa) to her brother (Will) spanning a 20 year period. Of note are the letters beginning with September 8, 1858
- Correspondence, 1846-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes copies of letters from Harrington's mother (Mary Louisa) to her brother (Will) spanning a 20 year period. Of note are the letters beginning with September 8, 1859
- Correspondence, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Business memo to Harrington Emerson from N.M. Rice (Atchinson, Topeka & Santa Fe Railway System) RE: recommendations of Emerson's & the effect on savings for the company.
- Correspondence, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Letter of recommendation for H. Emerson from W. F. Buck (Motive Power Dept. of Atchinson, Topeka & Santa Fe) - ( "To whom it may concern") endorsing the methods of Emerson's as "being of great value in systematizing work, reducing expenses, increasing output and..."
- Correspondence, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Includes correspondence to companies describing the services they provide.
- Correspondence, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Letter to Emerson Company from Mayor Geo. F. Cotterill, City of Seattle, regarding the excellent character of the Emerson Company.
- Correspondence, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Corres. with A. R. Demory of Detroit Timken Axel Co. explaining the methods & services of Emerson Co. and savings accomplished; with King Sewing Machine (cont) Co. discussing very satisfactory results from their experience with staff of the Emerson Co.; Evens & Howard Firebrick Co. re their benefits of Emerson services; to Wilfred Sellers from H. Emerson (8 p.) entitled - "A Great Modern Company" where Emerson describes the foundations of building the ideal company; & others.
- Correspondence, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Letter to Wm. E. Walter, Boston Symphony Orchestra re Emerson's 13 principles of efficiency, suggest running factories as if they were orchestras; letter to editors of Market World re Henry Dodge Estabrook's address; letter to editor of Outlook re Emerson's essay "Duration of the War", correspondence with Emerson giving advice and his philosophy and recommendations on building companies and operating businesses and other subjects.
- Correspondence, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Includes a 4 p. essay "A Circular for Indianapolis"; letter to A. W. Thompson explaining difference between the Taylor and Emerson Systems (5/2/16); and also re report on traffic records (11/6/16); to D. Willard (13 p.) re differences between the German and American methods (6/10/16); substantial correspondence with Prof John B. Waton, Johns Hopkins, and Prof. A. T. Poffenberger, Columbia, regarding methods of selecting satisfactory employees, particularly by analyzing photographs; to Arison regarding constructive criticism of his agency; to J. M. Davis (Vice-President), re report on connection and relations of the Emerson Company with the Baltimore & Ohio; to Charles R. Hook, American Rolling Mill Co., concerning wages, salaries, promotions, rewards; to D. Willard (11/16/16) re what is going on as to care of workers in some industrial plants, using Jon Patterson of the National Cash Register Company as an example as well as others.
- Correspondence, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Letter (8 p.) to members of Emerson Company explaining company policy regarding expenses and financial matters; letter to employees (men) regarding the war and advising them to apply for Officers Reserve Corps; letter re uniformity of contracts; to Dr. Yashima, Director of the Machinery and Rolling Stock Department; Imperial Government Railways (Japan) re wastes and financial losses on the U.S. railroads and offering his services and experience to Japan.
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  To R. V. Wright (American Engineer & Railway Journal) RE: time efficiency.
- Play Efficiency Life's Greatest Game, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  Address at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, February 9th
- Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Efficient Lives, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  Address delivered before the Business Men's League of St. Louis, January 5th
- Speech at Engineers Club of Philidelphia, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  Oct. 14th
- Essentials for Future Progress, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  In Business Science Bulletin, May
- Fundamentals of Civilization Required Also in an Industrial Activity, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  Address to the Administration of the American Rolling Mill Company, June 24th
- How Can Railroads of the World Meet Their Expenses, Introduction, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  Introduction to Talk On, February 7th
- Human Engineering, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  Address before the Harvard Liberal Club of Boston, May 7th
- To Those Who Perished in the Disaster of the Titanic, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  Memoriam, April 14th-15th, and Address to the Club of Printing House Craftsmen of New York, April 18th
- Modern Patriotism, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  Address delivered before the Civic League of Cleveland, February 28th
- Educational Demands of Modern Progress, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  Address before the Society for the Promotion of Engineering Education, at Boston, June 28
- Personality in Organizations, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  Address before Efficiency Society, November 24th
- Cotton Manufacturers' Association of North Carolina, Address to President, Officers and Guests of (Box 1, Folder 65)
- President's Welcome Address, Director's Meeting, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  March 9th
- Remarks, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  December 5th
- Rescue of the Fit: An Efficiency Duty, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  Address delivered at the 4th National Conservation Congress, October 1st-4th
- Robert Colliers Church (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Securing Efficiency in Railroad Work, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  Harvard Lecture, November 16th
- Address to the Society of Industrial Engineers (Box 1, Folder 72)
  April 27th
- Some Experiences of an Efficiency Engineer, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  October 24th
- Synopsis of Address before the Typothetae, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  October 14th
- Talk for Radio, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  March 7th
- Address for the National Association of Employment Managers, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  "What Economic Principles Must We All Grasp in Order to Correct the Crooked Thinking That Reaches from President to Pauper?", October 11th
- Address to the New York Railroad Club, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  April 21th
- Correspondence, 1951-1963 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  Letters from companies giving favorable opinions of the work, also Management Department, University of Arkansas requesting photo & biographical data of H.E.
- Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  With Hart Glass Mftg. Co. outlining the work EE will be doing; other correspondence to General Mills, U. S. Rubber and others asking for an opportunity to explain their methods.
- Correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Letters to companies explaining their services.
- Correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Correspondence, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  Letter to companies from EE; brochure regarding budget control and Emerson Bonus Plan.
- Correspondence, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  Describing services of Emerson Engineers; list of company references.
- Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Letters to to Grumman Aircraft, Crucible Steel, Pennzoil, Ashland Oil and others explaining services
- Correspondence, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  Includes letters of recommendations for EE from various companies.
- Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  Includes additional correspondence from satisfied clients (Gulf Oil, Johnson & Johnson & others), other correspondence explaining their services, known as "Emerson Balanced Management Methods"
- Efficiency Message to Bankers, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  Synopsis of address to Illinois Bankers' Association at Peoria, September 25th
- Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  Correspondence from companies giving favorable opinions of the work.
- Unidentified Speech (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 63)
  Administrative expenses & misc.
- Address before American Paper and Pulp Association, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  May 12th
- Address before New York Railroad Club, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  April 21st
- Address delivered to the Foremen of the American Rolling Hill Company, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  December
- Address, New York Railroad Club, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  April 22nd
- Address of Mr. H. Emerson, delivered before the University of Chicago (Box 1, Folder 64)
- American Wood Preservers' Association, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  Discussion of Mr. V.K. Hendricks' Paper "The Economics of Cross Tie Renewals," January 24th-25th
- Canton Address, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  August 2nd
- Cause of Modern Inefficiency and Its Costs, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  September 25th
- Address to the Cook County Real Estate, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  April 9th
- Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  Sample form letters and correspondence re the Emerson Wage Incentive Plan.
- Documents - E, 1908-1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Educational Demands of Modern Progress 12 p., Efficiency and Economy in Motor Truck Operation 23 p., Efficiency Fundamentals in Organization and Wage Payment 6 p, Efficiency Maxims 3 p., Efficiency Message to Bankers 8 p., Efficiency Method of Determining Costs to Eliminate All Wastes From Foundry Operations 4 p., Efficient Manufacture of Railway Transportation 7 p., Emerson Wage Incentive Plan 10 p.
- Documents - A, 1915-1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Abolishing the Twelve Hour Day In the Steel Industry 22 p., Alaskan Railway Problem 3 p., American Locomotive Fuel Record for 1920 12 p., Analysis of Dependent Sequence As A Guide to Fuel Economies 11 p., Analyzing Men For Jobs 2 p.
- Documents - L, 1908-1922 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Leather Belting Compared to Rope Drives 16 p., Let's Be Friendly Let's Help One Another 28 p., Locomotive Fuel As A Comparative Performance Unit for Different Railroads 7 p., Low Cost and High Profits vs. High Cost and Low Profits 16 p.
- Documents - J-K, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Justice, Common Sense and the Pay Roll 14 p., Knives (article regarding knives) 10 p.
- Documents - I, 1908-1920 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Increase of Railroad Net Income Through the Elimination of Waste 7 p., Increasing the Earning Power of Industry 5 p., Ideals As to a Modern Industrial Plant, Industrial Costs in Europe and America 23 p., Industrial League Meeting 3 p.
- Documents - H, 1917-1920 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Handwriting On The Wall 10 p., Highlights - The Emerson Wage Incentive Plan 3 p., How Can the U.S. Railroads Meet All Their Expenses 15 p., How I Judge Men 6 p., How the German Submarines Produced a Coal Famine in New York 8 p., Human Engineering 15 p., Human Parasitism Or Service 8 p.
- Documents - G (Box 2, Folder 11)
  A Graphic Story
- Documents - N, 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Nature's Type of Organization 7 p., Needless Foundry Wastes 4 p., Notes for Mr. A. W. Thompson on Use of Railways in Europe During War 18 p., Notes of Lecture at Chattanooga 13 p.
- Documents - E, 1908-1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Documents - O, 1903-1913 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Opening of the Alaskan Territory 16 p., Operating Costs 12 p., Operating Ratio, Standards, Efficiencies On Long Averages 12 p., (An) Opportunity 8 p.
- Documents - E, 1908-1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Documents - D, 1915-1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Dependent Sequence As A Guide to Fuel Economics 26 p., A Different Gauge Than 4 Ft. 8 1/2 Inches for American Railways? 23 p., Discussion of a Paper on Electrification of Trunk Line Railroads 7 p., Duration of the World War 13 p.
- Documents - C, 1902-1923 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Cause of Modern Inefficiency and Its Cost 8 p., Causes & Correctives of Industrial Wastes 25 p., Causes, Remedies and Devices 5 p., Chamber of Commerce of the City of Indianapolis 17 p. 8 p., Chicago, Rock Island & Pacific Railway: Report and Analysis 15 p. C (cont), Christinas and New Year Greeting from Harrington Emerson to All Who Are Interested in Efficient Organization 3 p., Clear Thinking As to the Railroad Situation (several drafts), Coal Resources of the Pacific 22 p., Commandment of Efficiency: Its Importance for Progress 100 p., Coming Back to A Peace Basis 11 p., Comments on the Commission on Industrial Relations and Its Failure to Agree 22 p., Common Want 2 p., Comparative Study of Wage and Bonus Plans 32 p., Comparative Study of Wage and Bonus Systems 38 p., Compensation of Employees 4 p., Cost Accounting. 3 p., Cost and Efficiency Records 41 p., Council of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers (to the) 28 p., Creation of Organization With Special Reference to Personnel 22 p., Creation of Wealth. 3 p., Crooks, Labor and Efficiency Troubles 14 p
- Documents - C, 1902-1923 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Documents - C, 1902-1923 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Documents - B, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Basic Formula of Industry 30 p., Battle Ground of Coal 11 p., Belting 16 p., Belting Compared to Chain Transmission 8 p., Belting Compared to Individual Electric Drives 12 p., Budgetary Control. 7 p., Business Outlook 3 p.
- Documents - F, 1910-1923 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Famous Firsts: High Priest of Efficiency 2 p., Financial Morality As Viewed By the French 10 p., Food and Industrial Competence 7 p., Food and Life As Illustrated by the Honey Bees 4 p. F (cont), For the Information of the Associates of the Emerson Engineers Who Began Operation January 1st, 1923 23 p., French Railroads 41 p., Fundamental Philosophy of Efficiency 8 p., Fundamental Principles of Efficiency 12 p. (Part of Proceedings of Railway Club of Pittsburgh)
- Documents - T, 1910-1922 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Taxes 7 p., Thirteen Principles of Efficiency 4 p., Those Who Are Taking Heart the Misery Brought About By Unemployment, A Wholly Unnecessary Condition 1 p., Traffic Cops and Why the Industrial Conference Will Be A Disappointment 15 p., Transportation (Railroads) 200 Word Summary 6 p., Twelve Principles of Efficiency (in various formats and parts)
- Lesson 5 - Despatching (Box 2, Folder 33)
  26 p
- Lesson 4 - Schedules (Box 2, Folder 32)
  34 p
- Lesson 3 - Planning (Box 2, Folder 31)
  32 p
- Lesson 2 - Personal Efficiency (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Lesson 1 - Introduction and Standards (Box 2, Folder 29)
  21p
- Misc. Unidentified Mss. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Documents - M, 1909-1921 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Manufacturers Association of the City of Bridgeport 3 p., Message From Mexico 4 p., Mexico and Her Problems 6 p., Mistake of Cost Plus Profit, In Determining Selling Price 12 p., Modern Efficiency and Scientific Management 2 p., Modern Production Methods (Theory and Application) 14 p., My Objections to the Piece Rate Method of Wage Payment 3 p.
- Documents - V (Box 2, Folder 26)
  (A) Visit to Mexico 24 p., (A) Visit to Sing Sing Prison 13 p.
- Lesson 6 - Standardized Conditions (Box 2, Folder 34)
  28 p
- Documents - S, 1905-1923 (Box 2, Folder 24)